good morning it is a 30 so I'm going
live during the pandemic I also realized
when I picked this time period it's a
little bit arbitrary just stay one
office like it's 8:30 let's go line down
let's do it every day at this time
because I couldn't think that I had
anything that conflicted I do it's today
every Saturday I have a 9:00 a.m.
appointment so in half an hour I have an
appointment so I'm only gonna be on for
20 minutes I'm just gonna quickly go and
post the link on Twitter for pepper
wants to come and hang out with me to
this morning so pumping I'm giving you
the right one and not the one that takes
you to our live project meeting and in
half an hour
what is the topic of conversation
creating possibility in the pandemic
creating a society that works for
everyone
by bringing enough people together to
work on a solution that works for for
you huh I'm not Jewish but I am a
feminist and we're all apocalypse
survivors this point aren't we I mean um
like a tiny tiny bit Jewish but I know I
I'm not goodness that's not really how
it works
it's my dad's dad that's Jewish kind of
follows matriarchal lines or you have to
actually be brought up in it
have above mitzvot and such anyway not
point this is just rolling anyway with a
name like that so I'm only on for 20
minutes I don't I was gonna make notes
and then I woke up too late my kid was
up to me last night
like my muscles just stay up all night
if I'm up for the next day that is not
how this this works but she's also going
through the same pandemic an apocalypse
a baby one she doesn't quite understand
it but she understands that the adults
are stressed so and in a bit of what
what is going on yeah she pops in every
so often Hey without without me asking
her to in any way is there her camera
let me just come beyond it more so I'm
there together Tech one I try not to
have her on on periscope
this is now on on youtube and periscope
so what I wanted to talk about today the
special day in my life
you will not TMI stick I didn't do i but
just registered just my truth that's
that day that part of what there's like
the technology cooperative there's the
solution raise the you know of like how
we have a conversation that generates
real solutions and you've have we've
done some of them would come up with
very powerful solutions it's just just
that it's the spark of an idea so now
how do we bring those ideas through
conversations and through tools that are
as easy as conversations into the world
how do we create a food app that
actually helped us coordinate with our
neighbors and and grow a garden or bulk
buy food how do we create a
transportation hub within our cities but
we're not relying on Amazon and so that
is what I'm focusing on that is my
project in the together text fear I had
a conversation with my brother yesterday
after our live board meeting and he was
like that's not my vision he was to get
hurt education is like everyone has
their own project and if the solution
racing creates a project that it's like
someone else has to take ownership of
that project can go with it look I get
that and that's not my vision because my
vision is that we do create something we
all we all own own together homesteading
in the city uh pisode one yeah that'd be
cool I'm not gonna actually be doing
that I'm doing this if there's not
enough food like even if I grew garden
outside in my yard if everyone else is
inside in Vancouver I'm not gonna get
that food because someone else is gonna
come and eat it that's a lot of labor
for in no way guaranteed food we need to
be growing on a city level not on an
necessarily individual level but that's
part of what we need coordination for
I'm hoping more people are waking up to
the fact that our governments although
again the best we have to do things like
come up with solutions for a pandemic
they are in no way adequate they can't
react fast enough they have to react to
me best they have to appear to be acting
the best interest of their constituents
so they can get reelected when they
never really like they don't have
perfect information they can't make
everyone happy and they can't react on a
time scale that we can right they
couldn't say okay let's start three
printing respirator parts that were
gonna get sued for everyday people
absolutely Canon did and then that
respirator companies probably give you
out of business cuz they're like when
we're gonna sue you for this I don't
think we need to erase the last hundred
years I definitely don't want to go back
to that time period you know female and
all I would like to move forward but
there is a lot of crap that has happened
in the last 100 years and I do think
that we can have the good without the
bad and a huge part of that and this is
what I'll be getting into in the next
week or so so what I'm trying to do is
have solution raising what I would love
this hour is 20 minutes but usually an
hour to be is working through the meta
solution raising with other people
online so having a conversation about a
conversation which is always what how
can a group of 10,000 people get
together and create something what would
that social media look like well we ran
through a contest that at the end we had
an idea that we actually wanted to put
our money into so that we could we could
use that project at the end and then
actually make it in the world actually
fund it work through the process of what
does it look like to have 10,000 people
have a say in in a project and ownership
of that project but also what I want to
do which is aside from solution raising
is this cultural piece of the personal I
think a lot of people who are in the
game be space in that space like people
need to Jordan Peterson you need to
clean up your own room before you can do
it
anything that's probably not what he
says but but that's my message of what
he says like clean your room that's and
although that's very important it's
important to be doing your personal work
doing the meditation and getting more
agency getting more sovereignty getting
more sense making capacity I think
requiring that everybody do that is
broken from the get-go
other people need is for everyone in the
planet to meditate in order for us to
move forward it's not going to happen
what we need to do is meet people where
they truly are so for me what that looks
like is
accepting that everyone's doing the best
they can everyone's worthy exactly as
they are and from that space it's a lot
easier to move forward because I don't
need to know if you're the right person
I know you're the right person or the
right you whether we are gonna work
together it's another question but like
there is no I'm better than you or
you're better than me it's just like
everybody's equally worthy now we figure
out the path behind that like now we
figure out where is your worth where
what know your worth is equal but where
do you where do you want to give more
value where where is your heart and soul
lie in doing doing what work what work
would you do for free if you won the
lottery what would you be spending your
time doing spend your time doing that
for the good of humanity even if what
that looks like it's not it's for the
good of humanity I would travel I would
buy an island I would okay well what
what actually is that there's no purpose
there but eventually you get down to it
the purpose of what what it is that you
actually you actually want to be doing
because there's these four questions
that I don't quite know how to work with
them in a group but it's part of the
part of the tech I would like to create
eventually is something that helps with
these four questions and the four
questions are never fully answered but
the purpose of life is to continually
try to answer them and never get to an
answer four questions are Who am I every
step you take along the way of knowing
who you are gives its own internal
reward you don't need the external one
in fact the external one starts and
melts away or you stop conforming to
what society wants you to be and you
start truly listening to what you are I
think it has a box of chocolates I only
got educated I am educated I have
university degree if that counts for
anything but I only got wise I only was
able to create my genius by purpose into
the world which still the process of
doing once I was no longer able to be
externally educated once I was no longer
able to read four to five books a week
and so I don't hold intelligence in its
normal capacity in its normal definition
to the high esteem everybody else does I
think everybody's intelligence
everyone has their own in fact the more
we focus on external education read this
book learn this philosopher learn this
Theory learn this the less we're doing
original actual thinking outside the box
theory
like I can't I'm a biologist by trade by
education and the amount of times it's
like well Darwin wouldn't agree with
that and like Darwin didn't understand
evolution how long ago did he die he
understood he was the grandfather of it
but he didn't understand genetics he
didn't understand epigenetics he didn't
understand a lot so how could you
possibly thank you
only on for another ten minutes today
again the if anybody wants to join them
for the last ten minutes there's a link
in the description in YouTube however
there's two links in the description one
of which will bring you together attack
which is the website that we are
creating the tech cooperative on so
we're live in for 20 minutes to discuss
our individual projects is probably just
going to be atrial Bentley and I think
yeah at this point but that's alright
we're growing and we're seeing we're
seeing how that works and then the other
link is to join in on this I'm trying to
figure out if there's a bitly or
something that instead of shortening the
URL it just I can I can do the back that
it's the same URL every day but the back
end is different like because the stream
mirrored which is what I'm doing this on
has a different joining link every time
and then people can't know to come on
because what I would love this time
period to be once I figured out a bit
more and once there's more of a
following although honestly that's not
the necessary part it's yeah the
following who wants to be on camera and
have the solution raisings live on
camera I'm gonna reach out to my friend
Kyra and ask her if she wants to do one
this week on mental health and emotional
support especially during this time time
I can we so desperately need it
a solution raising is we talk about what
is currently being done in that issue
what's good and what's bad about it what
the future could look like in our in the
ideal future what would mental health
look like support what would emotional
support look like and then we talk about
for half an hour the the adjacent
possible
what could we actually do together now
that's voluntary that
you could implement if you had 10,000
people and $100,000 and everyone we've
had so far we've come up with very
powerful solutions some of which I
already knew I'm like yes these are kind
of no-brainers and other ones I in no
way had access to you before we had the
conversation and that's the point of it
no single individual even though I've
spent hundreds and hundreds of hours
thinking about every different problem
on this planet and how we solve it and
how we come together and do that one
person can't actually create something
in the same way of course that 10,000
people can but if I created it I came up
with the perfect idea of a food app and
then how to sell it to you that's a very
different energy than us coming up with
it together you feeling like you have a
say in it and that you have ownership in
it and that is what we're figuring out
how can we get 10,000 people together to
create an actual solution in my mind it
won't be 10,000 people actually having
the conversation because I don't think
everyone wants to participate in those
conversations but almost everyone wants
the product at the end the food app the
transportation app the thing that's
actually going to help in the world and
so doing that in a way that the people
can be involved involved as possible
without them needing to be on camera
which means some of us need to be on
camera and so that's what during this
hour if I can find other people who want
to have solution raisings to focus on
them because I can have a different one
every day and whoever shows up in the
link are the people who are who are
progressing that and then part of what I
want to do is have the meta conversation
on how do we solution or a solution
raising which my brother points out it's
like we need another word I'm like I do
not need another word there's idea cafe
there's together tech having but process
raising that is what we're doing we're
figuring out together in a small group
five six people what does it look like
to have a process that a hundred people
can participate in and then with those
hundred people hello Michael you're the
first person I had died I don't know in
real well
real life is a bit of a stretch how are
you really how's it going it's going
pretty good I'm on for another seven
minutes how is your day going how's it
how's Quarantine life quarantine was
everything he left
like I'm fighting it okay like everybody
is like over isolated and we're
quarantine but quite frankly are you
really quarantined if you're in your own
home I mean no it's it's social
distancing its whatever whatever it is
but it's it still feels a little like
quarantine it feels a little like
someone posted this virus was like shore
teachers virus we both simultaneously
have to imagine we have it and don't
pass it on to other people and that we
don't have it and therefore are not
immune and Kathy's like we have it in
don't have it at the same time which
what is true yeah it looks like when you
quote so you know when you get a bit of
Sun you'll feel like a rebel cuz you
know it's illegal
well I hear it isn't you're allowed to
go outside there's actually a lot of
people outside were you Georgians
America right Canada Oh Canada so you're
kind of like Ireland don't jack country
is like this kind of country I guess I
mean I'm in Vancouver so there isn't a
lot of space that people who live in
Vancouver also are used to being outside
a lot so having been cooped up in their
house it's really really hard right if
you could come up with a solution for
any sector of society what solution
would what kind of solution would you
like to focus on probably care mental
care and there as well yeah yeah no
that's what me and Kira are gonna I'm
gonna contact her and see if we can do
one this week would you be interesting
coming and participating on it it would
just involve coming at this time period
yeah all right cool all right I don't
know how to contact you Michael all
right are you watching I'll subscribe
your channel so I have modifications I
guess yeah little work or have you were
Twitter yeah either or Twitter I'm at
crowd democracy and then YouTube if
you're watching YouTube it's this one
and it's got a touch at all and a bunch
of other it gets a little confusing it's
like solution cooperate or the
technology solution cooperative is its
own thing this is like my life journey
and me creating my
my mission of the world while living
life and so that's a little
it's a weird description for a channel
but it's like where I put everything
before it kind of becomes its own thing
out in the world sorry
it's your poly prophet : we're all
various kind of yeah exactly it's got a
weird name to please save us the world
by meandering through life which is
fairly exactly what it is it is the poly
pocket of my life it's just where i put
the things right where i'm i don't
notice my brain is both like amazing and
it comes up with solutions and it's a
little it's like an old car like a yeah
I've done a few solution raisings and
I'm really looking forward to the one on
mental health or emotional support
it's weird cuz we started it before the
pandemic and so in the first few even
the third one was on infectious disease
but it hadn't gotten in our
consciousness in the same way as it
currently is so it was like it would
kind of come up in it and now while
we're doing them it's like kind of odd
like it's like well what does that look
like in the current world and the idea
was what does it look like for the last
decades right and now it's like
everything's changed in the last few
weeks so it's like what does it
currently look like oh yeah so we kind
of be sorry are you playing a look at
the world right now like I'm in Resident
Evil again I go key virus broke out and
everybody's infected like I saw like a
look at this and you know a lot of
people I would stream Grove or what
happened so I was thinking apocalypse
and the world was ending like what would
you do but quite frankly what could you
do you just have to suck it up a little
bit I mean that's all though I mean I've
always in a weird spot I can always kind
of see both sides of almost every issue
but there's a lot of memes going around
that are like your grandparents had to
go to war all you have to do is sit
around and watch Netflix I'm like I
don't think you're accounting for how
difficult this is actually that not to
say that war is easy but war is
something we could end
if we really wanted to as a human
species and it's also like something to
focus on right like there's an enemy
you're trying to destroy it although
there is an enemy we're trying to
destroy it wins it's a lot like we can't
reason with it
sorry right I keep the whole workings
just down to human greed like dad is a
man purpose of it like is greed that's
for everything love to do it I have my
own thoughts of how we end war but I
would actually really love to do a
solution racing on how we end a war
because that seems like something that's
so I don't know whether you left on
purpose or you could just free follow
the link if you want to come back but
that war is something that we don't
think is possible to get rid of like
it's been here for so long we can't
imagine a world where our states aren't
going to war with each other and we all
of it is based on profit and greed and
we're although we feel like we don't
have power
we are the what is the Holy Trinity of
power we are the workers as we are
learning are they absolutely essential
for the economy we are the voters in our
democracies what's one more I miss you
what the third effect is we are workers
we are voters and we are consumers we
are the person who uses the product so
we vote with our dollar we vote with our
actual Democratic vote and we vote with
where we spend our time and trade our
time for money and there aren't
necessarily ops great options in all of
those areas but the more we can create
the tools to actually be empowered with
with in those sectors the better in
trying to show this is AP predator is
that you the person who was because that
wasn't I'm gonna guess since you're on
YouTube and dropped out sorry yeah
that's you okay
welcome to come back I'm gonna be off in
20 seconds so not today but I'm on every
morning and 8:30 working through what is
this pandemic look like what does it
look like to have possibly a pandemic
which is both dealing with like when
this happened I was kind of ready to hit
the road I was like alright great
everyone's at home just like I'm usually
at home let's get going and I realized
that one eye
in other levels of my evolution of like
okay although I can handle the pandemic
better than a lot of people because of
my nervous system and stress tolerance
which is low but then I've had to build
a higher capacity for it I put the
weight of the world on my shoulders
again it's all a part of it looks like
all right not not all on me and but
other people this is like the first time
they're really registering that the
world is fragile that our system is
fragile that we are biological beings
who don't really have a lot of control
over biology that we are part of a
political system that is in no way
adequate to address all of the myriad of
problems that are all intertwined like
this is a rather focused problem right
it's a virus we're getting to understand
it but all of the ripple effects of the
economic system and then looks like even
if you can go to work and do your
business that it's not going to be a
problem and it's either an essential
service you're the only one working
there you can't actually get the
supplies in you can't actually like our
entire economic system is a fragile
beast and it's been maximized for profit
not for efficient for efficiency and
profit not for redundancy and resiliency
and we are gonna see the effect of that
but we can come together and create
something that is like we can recreate
the means of production in a way that
isn't for profit and it's for purpose
which is what solution raisins are
showcasing is what does it look like to
actually have an impact on war I don't
know if we come up with a solution to
that one look I didn't think we were
gonna come up with the solution to
infectious disease like good luck with
it and we didn't come off the solution
we didn't solve rotavirus Cove in 19 but
we did talk about what we would have
what we could create together that we
would want to put our data into that we
could have a powerful effect on and more
same thing mental carry we have much
more of an impact on unless you need it
to be psychiatrists and psychologists if
it's more peer peer to peer and what's
the best thing we can do right now for
each other that's those are again like
solutions we could actually implement
right now during this pandemic when
people are gonna be both feeling useless
like their purpose doesn't matter
because I'm sure they can't go to their
job or their job this will work the same
way
plus the it--like the
physical isolation it's like we're all
in weird solitary confinement even if
you're not in solitary confinement with
your family or either alone and and
physically isolated or you're with
people who you normally don't have to
spend that much time with and now you
have to spend a lot of time with both of
those things come with mental mental
things emotional things and so in so
dealing with that so I'll be back
tomorrow at 8:30 I have our live project
meeting over on together Tech in seven
minutes it's a bit of a different play
harder for sure where you're gonna be
talking about our projects my project is
solution raising and having a bit of a
mastermind group of like what do we need
right now what's the solution that we
would need to move forward so I'm gonna
go and get ready for that participate in
that if you want to watch it the
description is in the YouTube channel
it's cuz it's hidden from the
description on the video on the YouTube
channel because it's its own YouTube
channel together Tech it's where we
actually if you want to watch the
solution right scenes it's where they
were posted it's also where we have our
live board meetings where we have our
idea cafes on projects and and all the
stuff that is under the umbrella
together chuckle so I hope to see you
over there and if not I will see you
tomorrow bye